<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/transform.xsl"?>

<article category="Portfolio">
  <section>
    <title>Research Theme</title>
    <body>
      <p>Broadly, I study the connections between pure mathematics and theoretical computer science with the aim to bridge the two disciplines. Currently, I focus on the interplay between programming language theory, algebraic topology, and computational complexity theory. Prior to this, I did exploratory research in analytic philosophy, modal logic, number theory, and machine learning in an effort to expand my skills and awareness of topics.</p>
    </body>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Research</title>
    <body>
      <section>
        <title>An Internal Differential Calculus to The Simply-Typed Lambda Calculus</title>
        <addr>./papers/cohdiff.pdf</addr>
        <meta>In Progress</meta>
        <meta><a href="/">Santiago Rodriguez</a>, <a href="">Steve Zdancewic</a>, <a href="">Stephen Mell</a></meta>
        <meta>University of Pennsylvania, REPL (2023)</meta>
        <body>
          <p><b>Abstract</b>: TBD.</p>
          <p><b>Keywords</b>: denotational semantics, coherence spaces, representation theory, banach spaces.</p>
        </body>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Density of Critical Points in Finite-Gap Solutions for the Focusing Nonlinear Schrödinger Equation</title>
        <addr>./papers/partitions.pdf</addr>
        <meta>In Progress</meta>
        <meta><a href="/">Santiago Rodriguez</a>, <a href="">Alexander Tovbis</a></meta>
        <meta>University of Central Florida, Department of Mathematics</meta>
        <body>
          <p><b>Abstract</b>: TBD.</p>
          <p><b>Keywords</b>: asymptotic analysis, integer partition, complex analysis.</p>
        </body>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>A Worlds Account of Thought Experiments</title>
        <addr>./papers/worlds.pdf</addr>
        <meta>27 June 2021</meta>
        <meta><a href="/">Santiago Rodriguez</a></meta>
        <meta>University of Central Florida, Department of English</meta>
        <body>
          <p><b>Abstract</b>: Besides logical arguments, thought experiments are used extensively in philosophy and science to acquire knowledge about the natural world. Many times, these experiments led to new discoveries. However, there are also various instaces of similar thought experiments producing wildly contradictory results. This raises the epistemological challenge of the reliability of thought experiments. Multiple theories have been proposed that aim to justify their usage. However, they fail to properly treat experiments about more intricate, nuanced subjects infamous for their vagueness and ambiguity. This paper attempts to address this difficulty by formulating thought experiments under possible worlds semantics in order to take advantage of the modal machinery that has been developed over the past decade.</p>
          <p><b>Keywords</b>: epistemology, thought experiments, modal logic.</p>
        </body>
      </section>
    </body>
  </section>
  
  <section>
    <title>Presentations</title>
    <body>
      <section>
        <title>What About the Middleman? Shrinking the Gap Between Theory and Practice in Machine Learning</title>
        <addr>./papers/cohdiff-slides.pdf</addr>
        <meta>4 August 2023</meta>
        <meta><a href="/">Santiago Rodriguez</a>, <a href="">Steve Zdancewic</a>, <a href="">Stephen Mell</a></meta>
        <meta>University of Pennsylvania, PL Club (Summer 2023)</meta>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Density of Critical Points and Integer Partitioning</title>
        <addr>./papers/partitions-slides.pdf</addr>
        <meta>February 2023</meta>
        <meta><a href="/">Santiago Rodriguez</a>, <a href="">Alexander Tovbis</a></meta>
        <meta>University of Central Florida, Integrable Systems and Potential Theory Seminar (Spring 2023)</meta>
      </section>
    </body>
  </section>
</article>
