<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/transform.xsl"?>

<article category="Person">
  <section>
    <title>Santiago Rodriguez</title>
    <meta href="./papers/cv.pdf">CV</meta>
    <meta href="https://github.com/unsonnet">GitHub</meta>
    <meta href="mailto:sa854119@ucf.edu">Email</meta>
    <body>
      <figure>
        <img src="/images/pf-square.jpg" alt="Santi in front of the Pyramid of the Moon" style="width: 150px; height: auto;"/>
        <figcaption>Teotihuacán, Dec 2022</figcaption>
      </figure>
      <p>Hello! My name is Santi, an undergraduate at the University of Central Florida, double majoring in mathematics and computer science. I conduct research at the intersection of pure math and theoretical computer science, with a current focus on programming languages, algebraic topology, and computational complexity.</p>
      <p>I'm also an avid listener of music, occasionally performing in piano or concert choir as a tenor II. I've been gradually building up a <a href="/music">music portfolio</a>, so if you have any new (or old) sounds you'd like to recommend or are looking for a concert-goer buddy, let me know!</p>
    </body>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Research</title>
    <body>
      <section>
        <title>An Internal Differential Calculus to The Simply-Typed Lambda Calculus</title>
        <addr>/research/papers/cohdiff.pdf</addr>
        <meta>In Progress</meta>
        <meta><a href="/">Santiago Rodriguez</a>, <a href="">Steve Zdancewic</a>, <a href="">Stephen Mell</a></meta>
        <meta>University of Pennsylvania, REPL (2023)</meta>
        <body>
          <p>Study on continuously differentiable maps over Banach spaces represented as stable maps over coherence spaces. Aims to identify a subset of continuous maps between Banach spaces and typed lambda calculi (denotationally modeled as coherence spaces) which composes to guarantee differentiability.</p>
        </body>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Density of Critical Points in Finite-Gap Solutions for the Focusing Nonlinear Schrödinger Equation</title>
        <addr>/research/papers/partitions.pdf</addr>
        <meta>In Progress</meta>
        <meta><a href="/">Santiago Rodriguez</a>, <a href="">Alexander Tovbis</a></meta>
        <meta>University of Central Florida, Department of Mathematics</meta>
        <body>
          <p>Analysis on the asymptotics over the distribution of critical points in finite-gap solutions for the fNLS equation. Consequently, provides an estimate on the probability of rogue waves forming in deep-sea conditions.</p>
        </body>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>A Worlds Account of Thought Experiments</title>
        <addr>/research/papers/worlds.pdf</addr>
        <meta>27 June 2021</meta>
        <meta><a href="/">Santiago Rodriguez</a></meta>
        <meta>University of Central Florida, Department of English</meta>
        <body>
          <p>Proposal on a possible / impossible worlds model for thought experiments. Also, introduces a method for carrying out modal inferences from thought experiments via counterpossible reasoning.</p>
        </body>
      </section>
    </body>
  </section>
  
  <section>
    <title>Presentations</title>
    <body>
      <section>
        <title>What About the Middleman? Shrinking the Gap Between Theory and Practice in Machine Learning</title>
        <addr>/research/papers/cohdiff-slides.pdf</addr>
        <meta>4 August 2023</meta>
        <meta><a href="/">Santiago Rodriguez</a>, <a href="">Steve Zdancewic</a>, <a href="">Stephen Mell</a></meta>
        <meta>University of Pennsylvania, PL Club (Summer 2023)</meta>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Density of Critical Points and Integer Partitioning</title>
        <addr>/research/papers/partitions-slides.pdf</addr>
        <meta>February 2023</meta>
        <meta><a href="/">Santiago Rodriguez</a>, <a href="">Alexander Tovbis</a></meta>
        <meta>University of Central Florida, Integrable Systems and Potential Theory Seminar (Spring 2023)</meta>
      </section>
    </body>
  </section>
</article>
